Steven P. Olson

Profile

Experienced professional pursuing a new passion

After a highly successful and rewarding career as a school music educator, I am following an inspired path in technology and software/web development. I have earned three developer certifications, and am working on my Quality Assurance developer certification. I am an active developer and web designer.

Employment History

Band Director, Hills-Beaver Creek School District, Hills, MN

AUGUST 2018 - PRESENT

- Nominated for Teacher of the Year
- Started the jazz band program
- Expanded the drum line program

Band Director, Pipestone Area Schools, Pipestone, MN

AUGUST 2011 - JULY 2018

- 60% growth in the grades 9-12 band program
- MMEA Board of Directors Region 3-4 A Representative (elected)
- Leadership article featured in the MMEA Journal "Interval"
- Symphonic Band 'Best in Site' at Large Group Contest

Band Director, Centennial School District, Circle Pines, MN

AUGUST 2010 - JUNE 2011

- Expanded the middle school jazz program
- Expanded the holiday band program

Education

Masters in Instrumental Conducting, American Band College, Ashland, OR

Bachelor of Arts - Music Education, Augustana University (SD), Sioux Falls, SD

Courses

Responsive Web Design Developer Certification (HTML & CSS focus), representing approximately 300 hours of coursework, FreeCodeCamp.org

JANUARY 2018 - NOVEMBER 2018

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework, FreeCodeCamp.org

DECEMBER 2018 - JULY 2020

Front End Libraries Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework, FreeCodeCamp.org

JULY 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

Details

917 E. Heatherwood Drive Brandon, 57005 United States (612) 418-0365 steveopr@earthlink.net

Skills

Quality Assurance

Detail-oriented

Adaptability

Dependability

Analytical and Problem-Solving Skills

Team Player

Communication Skills

Leadership Training

Visual Design Skills

Public Relations

Engineering

Links

<u>Portfolio</u>

GitHub

<u>LinkedIn</u>